evidon.com 2012-10-15

# Global Privacy | Data Control | Evidon

Welcome. The information below explains how Evidon collects, uses, and discloses information as we provide services to advertisers, ad agencies, ad networks, publishers, and other members of the online advertising ecosystem. We describe the notice and assurance services we provide to clients as our “InForm.” Wherever possible, we deliver InForm services to consumers from  [http://info.evidon.com](http://info.evidon.com/) or http://c.betrad.com. The information below is designed to help you understand how our InForm manages consumer data. 

First and foremost, Evidon is not a data company or an advertising company. 

  1. We do not sell data we collect in any individualized form - period.
  2. Evidon is in the business of keeping web media as transparent as technologically possible. Our objective is the same as yours – to keep your user experience safe and transparent. 

While we created this page to explain how we approach consumer privacy and data collection as we provide services to businesses, we recommend that you also review the privacy policies of the websites you visit and of the online service providers you use, such as your ISP. Close attention to the privacy policies of the sites you visit remains one of the best ways you can make informed choices about privacy.

What is the Evidon InForm?

The Evidon InForm is designed to create better transparency and accountability in the way data is used in the online advertising marketplace. Consumers will most frequently see the InForm when we serve notices in ads and on websites about data collection and use on behalf of our clients. Our notices provide the opportunity for consumers to learn more about data collection taking place, and where applicable, data that has already been collected to customize the ad or content experience. The Evidon education and transparency interfaces available through our notices, as well as the choice interfaces that we provide, are all part of the InForm.

An Example of Notices through the InForm

An example of when you might see our InForm is when an Advertiser or Ad Agency uses our Assurance Tag (described in more detail below) to deliver notice on top of an ad about data collection or use.

Initial notice will often appear as an icon with a text label, similar to notice on the upper right hand corner of the ad below:

Step 1:

Step 2:

If a consumer clicks through on the initial notice, they will see more detailed notice, often including invitations to learn more about the advertiser or specifics about the campaign.

Step 3:

If a consumer elects to learn more about the campaign, or wants to opt-out of targeting from the vendors behind the campaign, they will see a detailed transparency and choice interface like the one below. Further information about each vendor is also made available through this interface.

INFORMATION THE EVIDON InForm PROCESSES AND HOW IT IS USED

Evidon does not collect or use any personal information about individual consumers through our InForm. Instead, Evidon collects and relies on non-personal information to provide our services. 

What Information Does Evidon Receive and How Do We Use It?

To help our InForm remember the preferences you set through our tools and to provide aggregate statistics about consumer use of our InForm, we collect information about your use of our InForm for limited purposes. 

Website Usage and Analytics. We may collect non-personal information such as information about your browser, your website navigation within the InForm Website including log file activity associated with this navigation and geo-location information directed at determining the general location of users of the InForm. This information may then be used on an aggregated basis alongside similar information from millions of other users to help Evidon improve and develop our products and the user experience. This aggregated information will also be used to help Evidon and its customers understand how the InForm is being used. 

Preference Communications. If you change your preferences within our InForm Website (for example, an opt-out choice), the InForm Website communicates this preference to the appropriate member(s) of the online advertising ecosystem so that the request can be acted upon. 

Because we are also a service provider for other businesses, we do provide aggregate information to our clients about use of the InForm. This aggregated information may include basic reporting metrics like the number of consumers interacting with their privacy notices and the choices consumers, in aggregate, are making through these notices, but not personal information that identifies you in either case.

For advertisers, ad agencies, and ad networks, our InForm helps our clients build trust with consumers and ensure that their advertisements are not shown to consumers who prefer that their online or other activities not generate advertisements targeted to them. You can learn more about online behavioral advertising and how our services work by [clicking here](http://www.iab.net/privacymatters/). 

For publishers, our InForm also helps our clients build trust with consumers and provides detailed disclosure about data collection and use practices on their websites.

Cookies and Other Automated Data Collection Techniques

Cookie technology remains a fundamentally important part of how websites customize users’ online experiences. Through the use of cookies or similar technologies, we may store basic information about the choices you make through our InForm so that our InForm can remember your choices.

Our InForm uses a technology called an Assurance Tag, a piece of computer code that is inserted in advertisements that are served by our customers such as advertisers, ad agencies, and ad networks. This code enables us to deliver notice to you about the data practices behind the advertisement, including the detailed information and choice options described above. At no time during this process does Evidon know who you are or otherwise have any identifying information about you except your IP address and technical attributes about your browser request, including browser type, browser language, and date and time information. We do not associate this information with anything that would identify you or your computer for future use. 

Log Information

Websites you visit may also track product usage data to improve the services they offer or for other business reasons. As part of our services, we may analyze, on an anonymous basis, user traffic patterns through information collected by our customers. The related server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, and the date and time of your request. 

Opt-Out: Your Choices

You are welcome to opt-out of Evidon data collection regarding website usage and analytics associated with your use of the Evidon InForm Website. If you opt-out we will still record that the privacy notice associated with the particular advertisement or web page was delivered. The InForm Website will also continue to communicate the preferences you express to the appropriate member(s) of the online advertising ecosystem so that the request can be acted upon. We will continue to store the explicit preferences you set with us (for example, opt-out choices) in a cookie on your browser to ensure that we remember your requests as well. 

Click here to access our opt-out page.

Information Retention

Our business customers limit Evidon’ s collection, use, and disclosure of information through our InForm through our service agreements with them. We keep information we need to provide our services to our customers only so long as we have a valid business purpose. 

EVIDON InForm TRANSFER AND INFORMATION SHARING 

While we do not collect personal information through the InForm, as mentioned previously, certain information may be collected about an individual consumer’ s interaction with a particular advertisement as they use the tools we provide. To enable your control of how and whether you receive particular advertisements, it may be necessary for us to communicate your choices as described in Step 3 above. We do not share any individual level information we collect for any direct marketing purposes. We may share aggregate information about the use of the InForm with third parties. This information does not identify you or any other individual consumer. Evidon may otherwise share information it collects if doing so is appropriate to carry out your request; or if Evidon believes that doing so is legally required; or it is in Evidon’ s interest to protect its property or other legal rights; or the rights or property of others. Keep in mind however that we do not generally collect or possess information that would enable us to identify you or any other consumer.

CHANGES AND UPDATES

We may occasionally update our policies and procedures relating to Evidon InForm. When we do, we will also revise the “effective date” on these pages. The Evidon InForm is offered principally on behalf of and through other online businesses, such as advertisers, ad agencies, ad networks, and website publishers. We encourage you to regularly review the privacy policies of pages you visit on the Internet. 

CONTACTING EVIDON

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about Evidon or Evidon InForm and privacy, please email us at [privacy@evidon.com](mailto:privacy@evidon.com). In the event that we are still unable to resolve your concerns, Evidon is committed to cooperating to achieve a proper resolution of your privacy concerns.

Postal Mail Address:  

EVIDON, Inc.  
28 West 44th Street, Suite 800  
New York, NY 10036

Effective Date: January 11, 2011
